# WEE YING YING, EUNICE

Software Engineer

#### INFO

#### **EMAIL**

eunice\_wyy@outlook.sg yingying.eunice.wee@stengg.com

#### MOBILE NUMBER

+65 8112 7368

#### **DRIVING LICENSE**

Class 3

#### NATIONALITY

Singaporean

#### LANGUAGES

### English

Native

#### Chinese

Native

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

MySQL

React

Nodejs

JavaScript

Java

Spring Boot

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Motivated Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE) graduate from Nanyang Technology University (NTU) with 6 months experience in software development. Interested in the role of Software Engineer where I can contribute my analytical skills and knowledge acquired to cater to the needs of the company. I seek a company that will help me contribute to its development while concurrently aiding my personal growth.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical and Electronic Engineering), NTU

Aug 2016 - May 2020

- Pursued my passion for software development through electives such as web application design, software engineering
- Participated in events (e.g., ESCENDO 2019, EEE Overseas Community Involvement Programme, Innovative Challenge 2018, EFINITY 2017) and held leadership positions as technical support and group leader in these events under the NTU EEE Club
- Held leadership positions in Joint Dance Concert in 2016 to 2018 as programmer and vice-chairperson (planning) under NTU CAC Club

#### CERTIFICATE

#### FlexiMaster in Business and Financial Analytics, NTU

Feb 2022 - June 2022

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

#### NTU Final Year Project: EEEAssist Mentorship Database

Aug 2019 - May 2022

- Researched mentorship challenges (e.g., intrinsic/extrinsic motivation) among mentors and engineering undergraduates
- Design database website using software (i.e., MySQL, HTML, CSS) to encourage undergraduates to seek mentorship on various issues (e.g., career / academic advice, activity participation)

## NTU Design and Innovative Project: Wearable Device for Caloric Expenditure Measurement-Based on Data Analytics (Team of 10)

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

- Designed wearable device to compute individual's caloric expenditure
- Analysed users' data through software programming (i.e., MIT
- Implemented hardware (i.e., Arduino Nano, Grove GSR Sensor, Lightemitting Diode) and developed software program using Arduino Uno and MIT App Inventor (i.e., Block Programming)

# WEE YING YING, EUNICE

Software Engineer

#### **SKILLS**

- Database Integration
- Web frameworks
- Resolving technical issues
- Communication skills
- Teamwork
- Analytics Thinking

#### INTERNSHIP

## Overseas Product Intern (R&D Dept), Beyondsoft Corporation (China)

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

- Participated in product online and offline operations and provided users presale and post-sales service
- Assisted Product Manager with research, streamlining product requests, providing product verification, collect request feedback from the targeted market.
- Worked with Cooperation Manager on the expansion of the market through market research
- Gained insight into Quality Assurance and Quality Check-in for compliance based on ISO9001 and CE Marking

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer, ST Engineering

May 2022 - Present

- Participated in a 9 weeks Software Engineer Foundation Training Program where we worked in an agile team to specify, design, build and maintain software applications
- Graduation Assignment: Task Management System that emulates the Kanban Approach
  - Identity access management
  - Perform software implementation and testing
  - Generate relevant documentation, reports
  - Learn about the continuous improvement of software development best practices

#### Sales and Marketing Engineer, RainTree Photonics Pte Ltd

Sep 2020 - April 2022

- Assisting in managing the product portfolio and working on improving customer/end-user experience
- Working with different departments (sales, technical) to interact and support customers across the entire sales cycle